Matheus Costa Diniz

Mobile: 083 412 3288

E-mail: matheus.diniiiiz@gmail.com
PortfolioWeb: http://matheusdiniz.netlify.app
GitHub: https://github.com/MatheusDevios

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matheus-diniz-857070146/

Objective:

Passionate junior front-end developer with a desire to learn and grow in a collaborative team environment. I come from an Electrical Engineering background, with great experience in Software and Hardware Support. I recently finished an Online React Bootcamp and am currently studying Science in Computing at CCT College Dublin. I am sure there are many transferable skills I developed thorough my career and I consider myself confident enough to work as a Frontend Developer based on what I learned and the projects I got involved in so far.

Core Skills:

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Bootstrap;
- Programming: JavaScript, Java, Swift;
- DataBases: MySQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Core Data, Realm;
- Git. GitHub:
- Technical problem-solving ability;
- Logical and Analytical mindset;
- Leadership and negotiating skills;
- Good communication skills;
- Hardworking and quick learning;
- Team-Worker;
- Dynamic;
- Reliable and disciplined;

Education and Training:

CCT Dublin College – Dublin, Ireland - Higher Diploma in Science in Computing (In progress); NFQ Level 8

Results: In progress.

• Online iOS Bootcamp - iOS & Swift App Development Bootcamp - (2021/02 -

2021/06); NFQ Level 5 Results: Certificate

Belo Horizonte University Center – Brazil – Bachelor of Science: Electrical

Engineering (2013/01 – 2018/02); **NFQ Level 8**

Results: 1.1 First Class Honours

Employment History:

Job Title: FrontEnd Trainee - Brainnest

2022/03-2022/05 (Full-Time)

 Duties: Optimising the user experience. Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React to bring concepts to life. Maintained quality assurance through code testing and crossbrowser testing. Worked with software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released software and assisted in deployment of release fixes.

Job Title: Electrical Technician - Belo Horizonte University Center UNI-BH (Brazil) 2015/04 - 2017/11 (Full-Time)

 Duties: Interpreted electric and electronic schematics to diagnose equipment problems. Documented all maintenance and repairs performed on equipment. Tested, troubleshot and calibrated equipment in shop and field. Disconnected and removed electrical motors. Completed daily inspections of all electronic equipment.

Job Title: Hardware and Software Technician - Belo Horizonte University Center UNI-BH (Brazil)

2013/02 to 2015/04 (Full-time)

 Duties: Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution. Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems. Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.

Personal Projects / Continued Professional Development

- Author of a Light Sensor Project: A way to avoid glare on the roads due to light. (During my B.Sc (Hons) in Electric Engineering).
- Author of a Smart House Project Low-Cost Home Automation System. (During my B.Sc (Hons) in Electric Engineering).

Referees

References available upon request.